MUATH ALMOHSEN

RIYADH, SAUDI ARABIA Mobile: +966 555 076 766

E-mail: muathalmohsen@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://sa.linkedin.com/in/muathalmohsen/

Professional Summary

A qualified human resource professional with experience in most of HR functions, specialized in recruitment and manpower planning, have worked in local and multinational companies with financial, civil engineering and construction industries over the last four years.

Currently working as a HR Manager, responsible for three main departments; Organizational learning and development, Recruitment, Organization Development

Key Professional Skills

- Communicating complex information in an easily understandable manner
- High level laboratory skills including experience in talent identifications and training needs
- Excellent critical analysis skills with high attention to details
- Advanced skills experience in HRIS ERP; (Oracle / Microsoft Dynamic ERP)

Employment History

May 2015 - Present HR Manager

Asala Holding Riyadh, Saudi Arabia



Responsible for all HR practices (recruiting, training, and developing).

Jan 2015 - May 2015

Talent Acquisition Specialist

AECOM

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Key Responsibilities

Handling one of the biggest projects of AECOM Arabia - The Saudi Schools
 Construction Program with a projected staff planning of approximately 350 - 500 manpower, work in collaboration and act as business partner to the business line managers in the whole process of recruitment - (full cycle recruiting of mid and high senior level roles' responsibilities).

Jan 2010 - May 2013

HR Specialist (Recruitment)

Al Rajhi Bank Riyadh, Saudi Arabia



A=COM

Key Responsibilities

- Providing support in opening requisitions and preparing advertisements
- Reviewing recruitment policies for effective selection techniques and recruitment process
- Receiving and reviewing applications and creating a shortlist of candidates
- Organizing the development and implementation of the recruitment database to maintain a substantial pool of qualified applicants for sourcing and selection
- Organizing the development and implementation of the recruitment database to maintain a substantial pool of qualified applicants for sourcing and selection
- Managing and Conducting interviews and preparing final hiring report for manager's signature
- Preparing pre-employment tests for applicants, requesting references and checking the suitability of applicants before submitting their details

- Conducting orientations and briefing the candidates about the salary and benefits and responsibilities
- Negotiating the salary with the selected candidates as per the company salary structure and extend the offers to successful candidates
- Following up with candidates and maintaining recruitment status reports and updating database

Key Accomplishments

- Improved the accuracy of the recruitment system process
- Established good working relationships with customers/clients.
- Developed new quality standards for better quality and performance

Educational History

2013 - 2014

Master's Degree in Human Resource Management (HRM) Queensland University of Technology



Brisbane, Australia

Relevant Projects and Assignments

March 2014

Coaching Program - Executive Coaching and leadership Course

- Designed and conducted coaching sessions to a client
- Implemented the program using theories and models of coaching
- Worked individually and successfully achieved the objectives

May 2014

Employee Turnover Analysis - Talent Management Course

- Analyzed the issues and cost of employees turnover
- Identified the causes and evaluate the return on investment (ROI)
- Utilized valuable resources of (ROI) frameworks to evaluate
- Worked individually and successfully achieved the objectives

June 2014

Change Management Plan - Consulting & Change Management Course

- Identified the issues by conducting a consultancy sessions to the case
- Implemented Total Quality Management (TQM) approach as an intervention plan.
- Worked in a team and successfully achieved the objectives

October 2014

Expansion Strategy into a New Service - Strategic HRM Course

- Introduced the current expansion of the new service
- Well researched on the current academic litterateur of the strategic HRM
- Analyzed the strategic HRM implications
- Presented recommendations for successful implementation
- Worked individually and successfully achieved the objectives

November 2014

HRD Needs Analysis - Strategic HRD Course

- Identifying the key organizational issues
- Assessing the Implications of HRD needs
- Designed HRD plans
- Worked individually and successfully achieved the objectives

2004 - 2009 Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

Al-Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud Islamic University

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

THE PROPERTY OF THE PROPERTY O

AIRS°

AIRS°

Certifications

November 2014 Certified Internet Recruiter (CIR)

AIRS Training and Technology

Online Course

November 2014 Certified Social Sourcing Recruiter (CSSR)

AIRS Training and Technology

Online Course

Languages Arabic - English

Training Courses & Conferences

Courses in Human Resource Category

Sub category: Performance Management

October 2014 Performance Management

New Horizons Learning Centres Sydney, Australia

November 2014 **Developing effective HR policies & procedures**

Australian Human Resource Institute (AHRI)

Canberra, Australia

November 2014 **Building Team Performance**

Australia Institute of Management (AIM)

Brisbane, Australia

Sub category: Recruitment

October 2014 Recruitment and Selection

Learning Seat Online Course

Sub category: Business Development and HRD

November 2014 Workforce Planning

Australia Institute of Management (AIM)

Brisbane, Australia

Sub category: Leadership and Management

November 2014 The New Manager

New Horizons Learning Centre

Sydney, Australia

Conferences & Workshops

Seminars

October 2014 Human Resource Management Systems (HRMS)

The Impact of Big Data and Prescriptive Analytics on HR

AHRI Events - Brisbane, Australia

November 2014 Elite Sourcing. Enhanced Social. Engaged Talent

The World's Best Sources and Social Recruiters Come Together

ATC Events - Sydney, Australia

Professional Memberships

December 2014 Member of the Australian Human Resource Management Institute (AHRI)

Professional Member

November 2014 Member of Australia Institute of Management (AIM)

Professional Member

References

Paul Davidson

Associate Professor

QUT Business School, Management Phone: +61 7 3138 1248

Email: p.davidson@qut.edu.au

Suliman Alzzabin

Chief Executive Officer, CEO Al-Rajah Bank

Phone: +966 1 1211 7888

Email: azzabin@alrajhibank.com.sa

Mohammed Altwaijri

HR Business Partners GM STC, Human Resource Group Phone: +966 1 1443 2224 Email: maltwaijri@stc.com.sa

Falah Al Subaie

Dean of College of Eco & Admin Services Al Imam Muhammed Ibn Saud Islamic University

Phone: +966 11 258 6666

Email: ceas.dean@imamu.edu.sa